Amazing. Are we live? Can you give us
a thumbs up if you can see us
and hear us?
Very nice. We're getting some thumbs up. Very
nice. Wow. That's amazing.
Very exciting. I'm here with Eric. Eric, you
wanna introduce yourself for the few people that
don't know you already?
Yes. Absolutely. So, my name is Eric
Funny enough, I was actually employee, like, number
11 at Clay early on in the the
early days, depending on how you count it.
And,
I helped out a lot in the early
days of the product and,
helping agencies get on to the Clay platform.
And then my agency got so successful that
I left Clay and it went all in
on my agency.
Today, in my outbound agency, we send anywhere
from
eight to 9,000,000 emails per month on behalf
of our customers, and we're generating anywhere from
300 to now I gotta update the number.
Anywhere from 300 to 450
positive responses per day. We're also Clay's largest
user, and I'm the top,
person by replies on the smart lead platform
as well too. So we do a lot
a lot of sending emails and getting replies.
Amazing.
It's a star inside of Clay, also outside
of Clay. So let me give you the
background a little bit of this why why
we're doing this episode. Right? So we've done
a lot of content. I think some of
you might have seen how Clay uses Clay
or some are other webinars.
And I got some feedback saying that this
is all amazing. But, obviously, you're Clay. You
have to use Clay. So we wanna hear
from actual people that have the discretion on
what they can do, you know, what tools
they use, what they do. We wanna see
from actually them. So we've been, working on
two different series. One is what we're launching
today with you, Eric,
which is, like, having, like, the the technical
builders, like, the agencies that can show some
amazing workflow that they build with the clay
CLI
and any of the LLMs. So today, we're
gonna talk about Crockpot, for example.
Right?
For this one, we are currently, like we
would like to get more submission and more
ideas so that we can we can host
more people to this series that we are
literally launching today.
And I think it's gonna be amazing. And
we're gonna share, like, the the, you know,
the the the list of people that attend
with with with the agency. So hopefully, it
can also help the agency, like, find more
customers.
The other one,
we already started it, actually. We try to
get real operators in enterprise companies.
Right? Usually, enterprise customers of Clay to see
how they can navigate or maybe the internal
issue that an agency might not have, but
a big company might have. So for this
one, we have an episode starting,
I think,
next week or something, Nicole. If you can
put it on on the screen.
Nicole is the brain behind all all of
those things.
And so this one, we're gonna interview the
CRO of Maven.
And, he has pretty amazing,
similar to what we talked today, still about
outbound. But, obviously, he has massive sales team
and how he uses Clay to make them
super efficient when they're doing the, you know,
pipeline generation Tuesday, like, the the the the
pipe gen day, basically.
So
I wanna leave the space to Eric. You've
been early employee, but also more recently, you've
been one of the design partners for our
CLI product that we just shipped. So I
wanna hear from you, like,
you know, a lot of change in Clay
in the last six months.
A few months ago, I spoke to you.
You were not the happiest person alive about
Clay. Specifically, I wanna say I wanna say
how was the path of working on the
CLI?
What has been your experience so far? Tell
us, like, the the honest take about about,
Clay today.
Yes. And well, so thanks for having me.
I'm so glad we can actually have such
a raw conversation about this. So,
basically,
as
the agentic tools started picking up and it
was so easy, you could deploy anything on
Vercel. I I I actually like, we had
a Vercel account. We have a Vercel account.
I didn't even log in. I I don't
even know what the Vercel UI looks like.
I just swiped my credit card and all
works. And as you are able to set
these workflows so much faster,
and you didn't have to click around and
do all the the button clicking in Clay,
some of the magic of Clay was being
lost. And I kept talking to the engineers
and I kept saying, hey. You guys really
gotta pick this up. It it's gotta become
a much more seamless experience for somebody to
be able to build these workflows. It's it's
magic. I actually told Kareem. I was like,
it is a biblical experience
to be able to just say something to
Claude because God spoke, you know, the the
world into existence. I think, you know, words
have meaning. And so I could just speak
into Claude. I can speak into Grok. I
can speak into to Codex. And these things
just happen. You guys have to get this
done. And so then the engineers kept giving
me this runaround. And then when codex actually
came out with goal mode,
I was like, you know what? I'm gonna
use this tool called browser use. It's an
open source browser automation thing. And I'm just
gonna have it analyze my 15 most complicated
clay tables, and I'm just gonna teach it
how to to build clay tables.
So then I set it on goal mode
for an afternoon.
It learned how to build clay tables. And
in one day, I figured out how to
use browser automations to build clay tables automatically.
And the engineering team was telling me it
was gonna take months to get this done.
I DM the message to Kareem, and I
said, you are moving way too slow. You
need to move way faster on this. I
figured this out in a day. How do
you have a team of engineers who are
all x Facebook and all these cool things
that you guys can't figure this out? We
gotta do it. He said, come in right
now. So the next day, I came in,
told them what we need to see in
the CLI CLI project. Basically, on a weekly
basis, you guys invited me in to see
and try to break it. And there's even
a funny thing where I I broke it
because I, pumped a 100,000 record requests on
a Google Maps API, and then we have
to add on, like, a whole new node
to be able to accept this kind of
thing. And then,
the workflows has really come a long way,
and,
audiences as well, which maybe we'll talk about,
maybe we won't. But workflows has definitely come
a long way that it we literally have
gone from in our marketing agency,
we would say, you you have to submit
every campaign that you launch with the link
to the list that you're using, the clay
table, and the smart lead campaign. And then
the clay table dropped off, and now so
many mistakes are being made with Vibe Coding
and the clay CLI is so easy to
do with the workflow. We've gone back to
you have to give the audience link, you
have to give the workflow link, and you
have to have the smart lead campaign tied
to every campaign that you submit. So you
can dig back in and find it and
everything. So I think it's really come a
long way, and it's a it's a much
it's a huge improvement on the product, especially
where the market is today.
Amazing. And so when you approach the process
of, obviously, choosing the the LLM partners to
use with Clay, like, how how are you
I'm assuming you're experimenting with all of them.
Right? So what what about GrokBot kind of
click for you? What are how are you
thinking about the decision of the partner for
Clay, I guess? Yes. And so for everybody
who might be on this, I know it's
titled the GrokBot and Clay, but I am
for sure an equal opportunity
AI user. I've got the max account on
all of the major labs. I try everything.
We've even built our own internal benchmark so
that when a new model comes out, I
know genuinely, can it solve this benchmark? How
much did it cost to solve this benchmark?
What was the time? So we instead of
just vibes of, like, oh, I just feel
like this model is better, we actually know
internally, like, yes. We the we have three
benchmarks, and we know this model is the
best for this. This model is the best
for that, etcetera. So when they all come
out, we know exactly what to use.
And then I can talk about why Grokbot.
Should we bring up the slides
for that?
Yeah. Go for it.
Cool. So we're gonna be talking about Grokbot
today specifically
because and I'm just gonna wait for the
slides. Yep. So,
we we basically need the orchestration layer and
the the AI brain to be talking to
to then control the Clay CLI and and
all those other things. Right? So why do
I love GrokBot for this particular use case?
One, I've tried the Hermes agents and keeping
my computer always on. I literally at my
house, I have my, main computer, and then
I have my old MacBook m three with
a charger pushed into it with a with
a Hermes agent.
And keeping the computer always on is kind
of annoying, but then Hermes was always breaking
on me. And even setting up Cron jobs
on Hermes was so broken and all these
things. So as soon as I saw in
Grokbot that they gave you its own virtual
machine that never turns off so it can
run on that virtual machine so you can
go from your phone and you can switch
computers and all those things, that was one
of the first selling points that I said,
okay. We gotta we gotta start using this.
The memory is great. That's included here, because
you can work across chats and it remembers
everything that you were doing. I I'm pretty
confident that all the AI models are fantastic
at doing that now.
The fact that you can have a conversation
with it,
now that they recently added in the last
week, I do a lot of work while
I'm walking my dog, and just being able
to talk to it has been very, very
amazing to to just do that. And then,
of course, we can run the clay CLI
straight through the GrokBot,
app. And we we've made a bot that
is specifically
tuned
on how to use the ClayCLI, and it
knows everything about that. So anytime a new
technology comes out, I'm always thinking about what
did this new technology give us,
and how are we gonna change our workflow
because of that.
And so, anyway, Crockbot, that's the main things
that Crockbot gave us on these things. And
so the way we're mainly using it now
is I've got copywriting bots. I have list
building bots. I have deliverability
bots. We even have bots that if we
have a churn risk customer, it is
checking every day at noon and every day
at six on all their statuses and should
we be changing the copy, should we be
changing the the inboxes.
It's checking the list to make sure everything,
is good on there.
We're making bots for very particular niche parts
of the businesses as well as for individual
customers as well too. And so I even
recommend that for if you're running your own
GTM. I'm sure that there's things that every
day you gotta check the Facebook ads, and
I'm sure every day you have to,
check,
you know, some metric. And you you should
assign that to the bot, and you should
have a copywriting bot and all these things.
But if you have something super important, like,
in,
in a couple of weeks at Sculpt, I'm
running an event the day before Sculpt at
night. Everybody should come out. That is we
have a bot dedicated to that because it
is a special marketing thing that we need
to be on top of. And so the
individual bots I thought was was very smart
for GrokBot as well too.
And then I tell this big story to
a lot of people about how GrokBot helped
us double a customer's positive responses going from
a Tuesday to a Wednesday, mainly because I
was just running and gunning, and I just
saw that we weren't getting any as many
positive responses as we were for that customer.
And it just read our skill files in
my,
repository that we use for our company, learned
immediately, and that was the first thing that
I did with it. And so just the
fact that I could just talk to my
phone and it did all of those things,
and I got that outcome so quickly is
just one of my favorite things.
And then why are we using Clay in
combination with this? Because I know it's kind
of in vogue
for Clay's competitors to be chomping at their
heels and then for people who used to
be Clay's biggest fans to also be dunking
on Clay.
There's still a lot of problems with just
trying to vibe code all of these things
and not use a platform that has solved
a lot of the problems and and has
an
opinion. And so the the first problem that
Clay solves for us and why we're we
kind of went away and now we're totally
coming back is sharing your work.
Yes. I know you can share your work
in Git repositories, but, like, I'm not technical.
Nobody on my team is technical. We we're
not Git is really not a great place
to be sharing work that you can then
review.
We need to be able to share it
in a way that everybody understands. Everybody can
see how it's working, and it's it's all
in the same level playing field for us.
Number two is the observability.
So if something breaks, we need to see
why and how we can fix it. And
I I'll never forget. One time we were
running a campaign,
and,
we accidentally started emailing people who are on
the client's block list even though we haven't
emailed somebody on a client's block list in
the longest time. And I dug into it,
and it's because just
that,
campaign setup that we vibe coded
set up the wrong smart lead integration, and
it didn't put the setting on correctly. And
had we been able to manually
do our normal check through the clay nodes,
we would have obviously caught that. But because
we vibe coded it, we just expected it
to to work that way. It completely broke.
And we we we need that observability to
make sure that when we're sending campaigns that
are live in front of our customers prospects,
nothing is being screwed up because of that.
Then the third thing, I don't I I
have tried and actually this is even some
feedback I would even give to the AI
labs directly
is I have tried so many times with
skill files. And if somebody DMs me on
LinkedIn and says that you've solved this, I
wanna see it because I have yet to
see it. There's a magical experience in Clay
that when
an integration finishes running, it moves on to
the next part. And then when that one
finish it, it moves on to the next
part and doesn't wait for everything. I have
added dedicated skill files. I have added it
to my prompts. I've added it to my
system prompts. And I will say, when we're
running this workflow, I want you to find
the list of companies. And as soon as
you validated that this company is good for
us to reach out to, I want you
to go find contacts. And as soon as
you find a contact, go find the email,
and don't wait for the entire run to
finish. And the amount of times that it
still
overrides my skills and my prompts and and
all my other things, and it doesn't have
that magical,
efficient run that Clay gives us where it
just moves right onto the other thing as
soon as it's done. I I I and
I've tried. I've tried to prompt that a
million times, and it just hasn't happened.
And then finally is the rate limits. This
might not be a problem for other people.
Every time we buy a data provider, I
come in and I say, I will post
about you. I will pay full price, but
the only thing I need is I need
you to give me the highest rate limit
you can possibly give me. Basically, the the
biggest data bottleneck in our company by far
is the rate limits.
Then
we're because we're sending so we're we're literally
validating.
In order to send 500,000 or more emails
a day, you have to validate a 1,500,000
contacts every day to be able to do
that. We are ramming through these API rate
limits. And then the problem that you'll have
is if one team member is using the
API key in their vibe coded work flow
over here, and then one team member is
using the API key and some other vibe
coded workflow over here. You're gonna have a
lot of things start breaking, and they're gonna
get errors even though there shouldn't be errors.
You need to have a really sophisticated
queuing system and throttling system that will compile
all those things and then run it when
the API key is ready. Clay, if you're
using a native integration, completely takes care of
that. And it and it like, maybe for
email validation, other people can't relate on the
scale that we're at. But definitely, if you're
using any of these AI models to write
messaging or to create campaign briefs and you're
trying to update your CRM and all these
things, you will just blow through those requests
or you're not gonna be using them as
efficiently. If you're doing, like, say you're doing
five requests per contact or five requests per
company, you're just gonna blow through those those
rate limits, and you're gonna get a lot
of unknown errors of too many people in
the team or just vibe coding their own
solutions.
And so then this is just a visualization
of just how, in Clay things just move
on very quickly,
and then the queue as well.
That we've already been over. Okay. Great. And
so the way that we kind of think
about this is we give Grokbot
our because Grokbot is always on on a
computer, and Grokbot
is,
you know, using their own AI models under
the hood. We use it for the memory
and the context. If we need to build
a specific bot, we'll build a specific bot
for something or we'll build a bot around
a workflow.
It then builds that workflow and makes the
plan for all of those workflows, and then
we use Clay for running everything at as
concurrency we can, rate limiting the keys, having
the observability.
And then we can loop back on GrokBot
because it remembers all the campaigns that we've
launched and check the results and analyze them
and change things if we have to, and
that's kind of the symbiosis between,
the the tools.
And so we're actually gonna show a real
workflow. But before we go into a workflow,
we didn't, have time to put this in
because JEV is so new. But I also
think the new model from Typeface,
was really great for called JEV. And if
you haven't used it now, it's basically an
incredibly fast,
incredibly cheap AI model that it cannot code.
It can't make outputs. It can't do any
of those things. It literally can just give
you true or false statements or multiple choice
questions. And so what I love about JEV
in particular
right now off the rip is for ICP
definition.
So and this is what my sculpt talk
is gonna be about is how do you
build a perfect list of companies? Because once
you get a perfect list of companies, finding
the contacts is, like, child's play, especially inside
of Clay. But if you wanted to reach
out to companies and you said, oh, I
wanna reach out to construction companies. There's gonna
be a lot of companies on LinkedIn that
are under the construction industry tag, but then
there's gonna be a lot of them under
wholesale building materials. There's gonna be a lot
of them under consumer services. They're gonna be
spread out in all of these different ways.
You have to literally pull in every company
that fits any industry that it could possibly
be in the employee headcount and the geography
that you want. And then you need to
have an AI model score and see is
this a good fit or is this a
bad fit. My sculpt conversation was gonna be
about how we're using the cheaper AI models
to get that done. But now with JEV,
it's so much faster. It's so much cheaper.
It is just the the go to for
confirm confirming these ICP kind of things. And
so I know you don't wanna just see
me talk about all of these things. We're
gonna put it into action
instead. And so, we're gonna go over two
campaigns that we've launched, and we're gonna go
over how we set them up in Grokbot.
And then we're gonna go over even a
lead magnet that we've created because I've I
was talking to Davide about this as well
too. Clay has done a great job of
proliferating this job, go to market engineering.
But there is, like, first 90% of people
who call them go to market engineers, there's
no engineering in their go to market engineering.
And we need to see way more engineering
in our go to market engineering. And so
I think the biggest use case that you
could be doing is using
the fact that software costs are going to
zero,
and you can be building lead magnets for
people,
so that you can fill up your top
of funnel with maybe not just asking for
a meeting, but give them something useful as
well.
And so I'm gonna hop off of this
and then just start sharing my screen.
Let me see if I can pop on
over. And, Nicole, I think you need to
just bring that down for me. Right?
I'm just gonna try sharing and getting away
with it.
Nope. Nicole, can you help me out with
that?
Great.
Alright. So if you have not heard, the
AI labs are,
paying businesses for their business data, and there
are companies like PolyShares who
can you can become an affiliate of PolyShares.
And so instead of showing one of our
customers, I just figured I'd just show an
affiliate campaign
that we're running for them. And so, basically,
the way that it works is we are
trying to find partners as people who wanna
refer businesses that are willing to sell their
data to the AI labs, and we're gonna
go direct to companies
that,
PolyShift is very interested in. And we're gonna
be, getting them and seeing if they wanna
sell their data. It's pretty crazy.
It's like the starting price for a business's
data is a $100,000.
And,
Yeah. And then you can make a commission
off of that. It's it's all pretty crazy.
So the first campaign that we're gonna be
launching that we built completely with Crockbot and
Clay, and I'm gonna show all of the
evidence of everything that we did and all
that
is we're gonna be targeting bankruptcy lawyers. We've
already found that if we we accidentally emailed
a couple of companies that were bankrupt and
they said, this is perfect. We're bankrupt. I
don't care what happens with my business data,
and we're bankrupt, so we need the money.
We'll sell you the the business data. So
we use Clay to find companies
or law firms that handle bankruptcy,
and we're sending a super simple message. No
custom variables, nothing crazy so that the the
Clay workflow is super simple.
Hey, first name. Do you know anyone with
over 30 employees filing for bankruptcy recently? Not
sure if you know this, but the AI
labs blah blah blah. Then you could just
read this content if you're if you so
choose. We set all of this up. I'll
demo,
what Grokbot did after this.
And then we have,
this one where it's for the construction campaigns.
This is a little cheeky, but this is
the best performing template that we have. So
PolyShares will come out and they'll say we
want accounting companies this week or they'll come
out and they'll say we want interior design
companies this week. This week, it's construction companies.
So on this one, we say, hey. First
name, my accounts payable team wanted me to
reach out because you fit little checklist they
gave me. And then we're and then we're
gonna add some complexity into the clay workflow.
LinkedIn says you have number of employees employees.
You do construction work. You've been in business
since founded here. Not sure if you know
this, but the AI labs, blah blah blah.
And we just, like, basically give them the
pitch. Right? So in order to set this
up,
all we had to do
was and let me just pull this up.
So sorry.
I made a dedicated Clay event demo bot
that was trained on all of our Clay
CLI workflows and everything.
And I basically if you could see the
chat, I set up everything in the chat,
and most of it was without any input
from me. Right? Like, here is just me
asking what I was spending credits on and
that kind of stuff. But most of it
was just being taken care of by the
bots, talking to each other, just doing everything.
And so I asked it for just a
overview of the demo story so it can
just go through,
so I gave it the demo story so
that we don't have to sit and wait
for, like, what did GrokBot say, and what
does this look like, and what does that
look like. But literally, all I just gave
it was I it says I gave it
two live PolyShare outbound lanes, which was basically
just the, copywriting.
And you said, hey. You wanted to launch
one towards bankruptcy companies. You wanted to launch
another one with construction companies, and I noticed
that there was number of employees as a
custom variable and then founded year as the
custom variable.
We were using the Clay CLI, and we
used JEV to be able to,
verify that they all fit our ideal customer
profile.
And so we pulled the company list from
an internal, database that we have. We found
400 bankruptcy firms. We had 400 construction firms.
And then we set up these workflows in
here, which I'll demo those workflows absolutely.
And then it all landed in the smart
lead campaign.
As you can see,
I'm trying to see if there's anything else
that you might wanna see. Maybe if somebody's
interested, I can show us editing the campaigns
that you could see, like,
you know, how simple it is to to
put all of these things together.
But then
all of that resulted
in let's go back over here.
All of that resulted through this workflow being
built. I had nothing to do with this
workflow being built. It was completely built by
GrokBot and the Clay CLI.
So it just took the CSV upload, and
then it got ready to build the the
dev system body right here. And then we
did a JEV API call, which I'm definitely
not gonna open because I think it'll docks
my API key. We did a Jev API
call, and then we had an if then
statement of did it pass our gate or
did it not.
We then use Prospero to find the contacts
that we wanted at the company. We use
Jev again to make sure that those contacts
are genuinely good fits for this kind of
outreach. We use Prospero to then find the
work email and then LeadMagic to do the
email validation,
and then we drop them off inside of
smart lead over here. And,
you know, there's a lot of different tools
of going in between these things, and I
obviously recommend you're using the ClayCLI and,
and JEV for the ICP confirmation and those
kind of things.
Just a couple points on these data providers
here. LeadMagic, in my opinion, has the best
catch all validation of any tool that we've
tried. We literally ran a test of,
like, looking at the last 1,000 positive responses
that we had gotten. And if we had
not validated them with LeapMagic, we would have
missed, I think, like,
a 100 of them, if we just trusted
the other tools like MillionVerifier
or ZeroBouncer, all those kind of things. And,
Prospero has some really good email finding too
because they have some, like, bounce band things
in that as well. But then over here,
this workflow basically looks the same because all
this one added in
oh, wait. No. That was the construction one.
The only other thing to call out over
here was we were able to address the
custom variables
just right here as well too. We have
the founded year and the number of employees,
and it nailed it on that side
as well.
And then we basically get these campaigns
dropped into our smart lead, and we could
just verify
that this looks perfect.
Let's even check, you know, is this
a bankruptcy law firm?
Texas bankruptcy lawyer. We nailed it. Great. Okay.
And then if you even wanna check
some construction firms in here too,
construction, Arbor Homes, Ferrero construction,
these are all construction companies as well. So
they nailed it on this one as well
too. And then let's just verify that it
dropped in the custom variables correctly. You have
employees. You've been in business since 1977. Oh,
this would be such a good target. We
maybe should even,
cold call them. Oh, these would be a
great target too. Jeez.
I want these people's data. We would make
so much money getting their data. Okay. Great.
And so
as you can see, it's super easy to
use the Clay CLI to create campaigns. But
like I said, there's not enough engineering and
go to market engineering today. And so the
other thing that we were using Grokbot for
with the Clay CLI is I'm making these
things that I call go to market hubs.
And so literally what we're doing here is
I'm trying to think about what can I
send to a company that would be valuable
in and of itself without them having a
conversation with me, and we could just spread
value
everywhere, and and they could just love us
for for spreading value? So we're we're making
these HCM hubs,
which is automatically building a list of comp
contacts and companies that this company would wanna
reach out to. So we have Pendo, and
we're saying that they would wanna reach out
to all of these different companies. But not
only are we doing that, I've included some
of the mobile phone numbers, and then I'm
also including,
we have a super base. If you go
to coldoutbound.com
backslash free lists, we have a super base
of every new hire in the last ninety
days. We're also telling them
everybody who's new in their role
in their target market as well too.
And then when it says warm,
I'm also pull I'm using Clay to pull
every person's
job experience
on their sales team, and then I'm finding
out what is the past experience of every
person on their sales team, what schools do
these go these people go to, and what
cities are these people located in so that
we can layer on and we could say,
oh, this, like, this person, they also went
to the University of Georgia. This person went
to the University of Georgia. This one this
purse your sales rep went to Brigham Young
University. This person went to Brigham Young University.
And we're showing the overlap of the
the the warm overlaps as well too. And
then we've even got, like, open jobs
on here as well too.
I've thought about running this playbook for the
longest time,
and,
it could never really become possible because intelligence
wasn't there. The clay CLI didn't exist, and
we weren't able to programmatically pull in this
data. But then also
to confirm that we were actually sending good
fit companies
to
to these people completely cold, I needed something
like JEV to be able to score them
for so cheap. And so, the combination between
these AI models getting good enough, being able
to work on a computer, being able to
work while my 10 old was screaming, crying
in the car, and I was still able
to do everything yesterday was just a magical
experience because the the compute like, I was
I had no computers. It was just all
working from my phone RockBot.
And,
now we have JEV to be able to
verify it. So when I send these hubs,
they actually genuinely look like great,
great lead magnets for people. And so,
yeah, that's just a a sample into what
we're doing with the ClayCLI, how we're using
GrokBot and and all these tools, and happy
to open it up. Maybe even for the
rest of the time for some questions so
we can live demo some things or something.
Yeah.
In the meanwhile, if you oh my god.
The color coding is terrible.
I'm so sorry. I'm gonna try to fix
it. To install the clay CLI, you should
just literally go to cloud codex, cursor, crop,
but whatever you use. You literally ask it,
like,
set up the clay plug in by following
the steps. Then you have this link, github.com,
clay run, agent plug ins. We can do
a better pop up, Nicole. I'm so sorry.
I did this mess.
But, like, it's very simple to set it
up. For the peep so there's some people
on the line that are maybe, like, less
familiar with Clay. Can you explain what does
grok Bot do? Like, does the workflow happen
inside of Grok Bot? Does Grok Bot help
you build the workflow in Clay?
Like, who does what, basically?
Yes. Absolutely. So I I say that Clay
is the the place in the cloud where
the workflow is actually gonna happen, where you
have your, like, raw materials of of the
things that can actually happen. And Grokbot is
the thing that knows how it works and
knows how to build it. So with Grokbot,
I do all of my planning, and I
just talk to it. And I say, okay.
We wanna pull a list together of bankruptcy,
lawyers, and we need to clean them because
there's gonna be all these issues with it
and all these other things.
Use Jev to clean it in Clay and
and all of that. So GrokBot is just
planning with me and knowing what we're gonna
build, and then it goes into Clay and
it actually builds the thing. So now at
any point with those workflows that I just
showed you, I could take any audience of
people that fit and and then just shove
them through that workflow. Their emails are gonna
get validated. I could I could accidentally shove
marketing agencies through all of those workflows, and
Jeff is gonna kick everybody out and make
sure that we're not sending emails to anybody
who wouldn't be a fit.
So that's, like, kind of the the difference
between both of them. Yeah. Is there any
way to think about it? The model is
effectively the thing that prevents you from having
to click into the UI and creating the
notes and creating all the, like, the building
blocks of the workflow.
It's kind of like you have a conversation
with it. I also actually do use a
a lot when I'm walking my dog. And
I have a conversation with it. Sometimes I
use Claude. It doesn't matter. Right? And and
it understands how Clay works, can build the
workflow on Clay. Then when you go back
to your desktop, you can actually see the
workflow. You can fine tune it. You can
audit if everything is going correctly.
And, do you also use,
some sort of, like, learning loop? Like, meaning,
do you have then group all loop for,
like, issue how how do how did you
improve by two x the reply rate that
you said in your slide? How does that
happen?
Yes. Okay. So the reply rate being improved,
and that that was I wasn't sure if
we should put the scope in here. I
thought I was gonna actually talk way too
long, but I think we finished way too
too quickly. And so
the the way we're able to two x
that reply rate is because we can give
all of the knowledge to Grokbot
of how we run campaigns.
And because
another thing I didn't even mention is that
the routines are so easy to set up.
I would say on on Claude and Codex,
to give them credit, the routines are very
easy to set up. But on Hermes, I
just like, the routines would break all the
time, and all my cron jobs would break.
And so to what we literally do is
now on a daily basis is we have
the Grok builds CLI
in our Grok bot computer because Grok bot
usage gets used up pretty fast, but the
Grok builds you know, you get a lot
of usage through that. So it'll run a
routine, and it'll say, okay. Hey.
This is all of the messaging that we're
allowed to use for all of our customers,
and here's all of the list filtering that
we're allowed to do for our customers.
Can you run through their campaigns and anybody
who's not hitting the positive responses they need
to be hitting? Can you suggest improvements based
on those campaigns?
And then it runs through. It says, okay.
Like, I analyze the the list that's in
this maybe we can tighten this list a
little bit. Or I analyze the copywriting that
we're using. This seems to not be resonating,
and we're trying for instance, we're we're literally,
like, the way the campaign that we doubled
the reply rate for is for a PR
company.
And we split tested, like, does it even
matter
mentioning an industry branded
publication that somebody would want to be featured
in, that we AI generate based on their
industry and their company description, all those things?
Those adding cost to the campaign. Did it
even matter? And it's like, yes. We get
a 40% increase in responses when we name
an industry publication versus just naming the Wall
Street Journal and TechCrunch and all those things.
We were able to catch that with GrokBot
because it's it's running these tests. And so
we have maybe two or three customers
where GrokBot literally has, like, their entire messaging
doc, all of the tests is allowed to
run, all of the list filters is allowed
to run, and it just automatically runs campaigns.
Most of our customers have not allowed us
to just opt in to that happening. So
we still do have, like, a loop of
suggestions, and then we see which suggestions are
good, and then we we deploy it.
We should be able to talk about this
because I got approval from legal. But clickup.com
was one of the first companies that we
implemented
this self learning.
Let it just do whatever it wants. It
it it has all the approved messaging. We
know exactly who the TAM is, all these
other things. And we were get we went
from quite literally
10 positive responses a day up to, like,
40 because we just let it learn. And
I I could go into some of the
insights there that I think everybody could could
learn from, but
not sure where in the direction you wanna
go, but I we learned some insights on
that too. Yeah. Why don't you why don't
you elaborate a little bit? Like, how does
it mechanically work like this self learning loop?
Yep. So whenever you're building these self learning
loops, whether it's on Grokbutt or any of
your other AI models,
you first the first thing I tell everybody
is you need to contain it into, like,
this is the only thing that you're you
you, like, the like, you cannot just wake
up one day and if I said that
my ISP
is colleges, that you start just emailing the
marketing agencies. So you have to be very
clearly defined on that.
Then you also wanna be clearly defined on
what the goal of the campaign is. So
if you if your goal is to book
meetings, one of the first things that AI
is gonna come up with is gonna say,
like, well, don't go for the meeting. Maybe
try to see if they'll, you know, be
interested in some information first. And it's like,
no. We have to be going for the
meeting on this one. So you also wanna
outline, like, what's the goal that we should
always going towards as well too. And then
the third thing that I tell everybody when
they set this up is you really wanna
have all of the data done upfront. You
don't wanna mess around
with, like,
Grokbot coming up with an idea and saying,
oh, I'm gonna pull their meta ads library
data, and we're gonna run campaigns based off
of that. You wanna use something like a
database of your own or a clay audience,
and you wanna have everything that you could
possibly imagine done upfront. What's their meta ad
library look like? What have they built their
website off of? Is this person new in
their role, or have they been there for
a long time? Did they just get a
promotion?
Everything you can possibly think of, just get
it all done upfront. Because what I don't
want Grokbot doing is making a game time
decision, and then it either overspends money on
things that I I didn't actually want it
to pull the data on, or it'll just
pull the data incorrectly. We just don't want
that to happen. So
number number one step is
outline what it's allowed to do, what decisions
it's allowed to make, what's the goal that
we're going for towards, and give it the
entire TAM with all the filters upfront.
Any questions about that?
No. I can have an
let let me share the screen one second.
I wanna show how we do it internally.
So we have a big sales team and
a big CR team. Right? And so, partially,
like, we have to make sure that they
are happy.
I'm sure some people can relate to this.
So this is literally can you see my
Slack, by the way?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. We can see the Slack.
So this is a channel where the clear
the hours, you can see that they put
this nice image
of me as the terminator. But, like, basically,
they put the feedback on, like, these are
the things that are broken with our place.
Right?
And so
what happens
is sorry. Let me try to unshare.
We have the group that on a daily
basis, a daily job, it goes to read
the things that are happening in the channel.
Some of them is just like, we need
to do a completely different thing with the
play. Sometimes there's an issue with enrichment or
this type of account we shouldn't include in
this play. And so it is able to
understand when it's an actual bug,
something that is actually broken and not just
the opinion of an SDR. And in that
case, it just fixes itself. It goes into
the workflow and it fixes it so that
the bug stops happening.
So we you can also you if you
have a sales team, you can also use
this type of, like, human in the loop,
which they give you, like, tickets. They say
this is this is bad. And so you
can have RockBot either, like, tell you a
list of the things he wants to,
fix, and then you can approve it or
just do it itself.
There's another thing I wanna show, which is
someone is rightfully asking, like, how do we
know that this black box is not consuming
all my credits and things like that? Like
like, what's going on?
And so I can show you, like, a
workflow we built with the Clay CLI
to,
basically understand the people that are signed up
through the Clay CLI or to the MCP,
the ones that are working in tier one
and tier two accounts,
to try to convert them into enterprise accounts.
Right? And so what you can see is
that you have this graph where you can
see and understand, like, what's going on. Right?
If you do not understand,
you can just ask either the your CLI
or you can ask our internal agent.
Right? But and you can see
okay. So what went through which step? Right?
There were 65 runs. These are the credits
that were spent. These are the executions.
But I can also see
literally
every single execution.
Right? What happened? What party took? What was
the credit spent per day? What was the
duration of the workflow when we have failures?
Right? Those are the things you can feedback
to your coding agent
to try to have a self learning loop.
So we we try to build this CLI
with the idea that Clay is not gonna
become a black box. Because at that point,
like, you just use, like, cloth directly. And
then you have your black box.
It's very important to us because we have
a lot of sellers. Like, we have a
lot of customers. We wanna make sure that
if something breaks and it does break, that
we can identify what broke, like, pretty fast.
Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely.
And now going back to the self learning
loop, somebody was even asking, well, what do
you
what do you manually still do, and what
do you let AI do? And so
one big thing I would say is copywriting.
That AI is still
you're it's basically gonna still write even the
best messaging. It's just gonna keep saying the
same kind of template. Right? If we noticed
in my copywriting that I put there, it
was a little cheeky. Right? And some people
might disagree with my copywriting there. But me
saying my accounts payable team wants me to
reach out and connect with you so we
can send you money.
AI would never come up with that message.
Like, that that's, like, not a thing they
would ever
suggest to you. And so when we are
building these self learning loops, we do say,
like,
hey. Here's a spot in the email where
you can try a value proposition or you
can try a pain based question or or
those kind of things. But the actual framework
of the email, I don't want you changing
this because we wanna we wanna test this
as a template, and we are manually writing
those. So and and we have a couple
of them that we kind of use so
that we can brainstorm
from them and kind of reuse them. So
this idea of the accounts payable thing won't
work for any other customer. It's just the
fact that, like, this company's buying data that
they can do that. But another one that
I really
I personally use is sending the whole message
that I wanna get across them in the
subject line and then just adding a little
bit of a sentence in the body text.
So, like, right now, we have a campaign
that's crushing for us right now.
We generate over a 100 leads a day
for public relations companies to, like, get people
listed in, like, Forbes and Wall Street Journal
and all these other things. We we will
email other PR companies and say,
is your cost per lead below a $100?
And that's the whole the whole subject line.
Hey, Davide. Don't respond if your cost per
lead is below a $100. But if if,
don't respond if it's below, but if it's
above, just email me back. And then that's
literally just getting people who are like, oh,
it's it's above that. What's what are you
talking about? I was like, great. Okay. And
then we start the conversation with them. AI
will never come out with that kind of,
like, pattern
interrupt odd email that,
people will do. So when we're doing something
with ClickUp,
we will we will say, hey. Here's the
spot that you can change this value proposition,
or here's the spot that you can change
the the pain based thing. But this template,
you're not allowed
to touch. We manually wrote this template, and
then it can try value propositions there. Another
real quick example of, like,
we're running something for a medical waste disposal
company, and they gave us three value props
other than price because I wanted to go
in there and be like, what are you
paying for medical waste disposal right now? And
we're gonna beat that price, but they didn't
wanna run that for, you know, good brand
reasons. And so they said their value propositions
are the same driver shows up every week,
so you don't have to give a tour
to every,
new driver that the company sends.
They're they guarantee that what they quote is
what they're gonna invoice for.
And then third is that sometimes these companies
have multiple companies picking up different medical waste,
but they can handle any kind of medical
waste. They're licensed for everything. They have certificates
for everything. Right?
Then we try all of that messaging and
just see which one resonates with who. And
and it can it has the templates change,
but it knows to slot in the value
propositions. And those are the the value propositions
allowed to use. We know after testing for,
like, four or five days that people mostly
care
about the the fact that the quote doesn't
match the invoice that they're actually receiving. And
now we're gonna scale that. We're gonna pump
it up, manually write a new template, try
a couple of other value propositions, then let
that go into the self learning loop in
there.
There's one question,
how to set it up. Right? So I
wanna share, like, my experience with it,
for a sec. Hopefully, it works. Can you
see my GrokBot?
Yes.
Okay. So Clayton is supposed to be my
good market engineer. Right? Great. Yeah. And
so
you created.
Right? I created it. Then what should I
do? Use the Clay CLI to build and
update GTM workflows and make money. This is
all that I told it.
Right? Then it installed.
Right? It asked you for the API key
for Clay. You can save it securely.
Right? And then once it's done, like yeah.
This is literally the authentication. So now it's
connected to the Clay go to market workspace,
which is what we use.
And then we are live. And then he
literally said, these are three option.
What should I start building?
Then I was typing hold off, and then
the guy decided, okay. I'm gonna do the
first one, and he literally built it.
Right? Yeah. And it's very, like, it's it's
very basic.
But then he literally, like, you know, he
put his own name into the thing. And
it didn't work. It's very busy. It's very
basic, but, like,
it helps you get started. And that's, I
think, the beauty with these coding agents. Like,
you can't just get started and then iterate,
and it's just a conversation.
Right? And they can be a little bit
of, like, design partners with you so that
you can get up to speed on tools
that maybe used to be a little bit
complex, like, claim much faster.
Does it make sense, like, that this is
kind of, like, was my, like, zero to
one with with the CLI here?
Yeah. No. And I and and that's the
other thing too is, like, because these models
will also teach themselves things, just getting the
practice so it gets the reps in. So
for instance, like,
I don't really want sometimes when you use
the Clay CLI, actually a big advice for
anybody getting on it, sometimes it'll use the
node a little bit too often that I
don't really want it to be using the
node for that. So then I'll see that.
I was like, hey. This is the only
reason we use.
It'll it'll, like, use for, you know, ICP
classification stuff. And it's like, no. No. No.
Choose a regular four o
mini open AI node or use a Jeff
node. Like, don't do that. Right? So, like,
you get those reps in so you can
start teaching it your style your styles and
your preferences and and all those other things.
Another recommendation I would have
if you are just getting into workflows
is tell your favorite AI to review all
of the clay tables that you've already manually
built and build out a preference chart for
you. Because, like,
you might like one data provider over another
and you always there's some, like, different preference
that you want. You don't wanna just take
the email waterfall off the shelf or or
you don't wanna use the mobile phone number
waterfall off the shelf. So then if you
have it look at the ones you've manually
made and learn from that, then it can
start making, like, a preference guide for yourself.
Yeah. Or, for example, if you have functions
that are managed by ops. In my case,
I have ops
as a function for
adding someone to a campaign.
Right? They have a function for scoring and
routing to sales, and I don't wanna reengineer
it. So I just told it, like, whenever
we have to score it or add to
a campaign, this is the function you need
to use. Then once it memorizes it, then
it it it's kind of like one shot
in going forward. Yeah. For sure.
Just a couple of things in the chat.
I I always love question and answers. Is
calling the dev API through Clay's HTTP better
than GrokBot calling it directly? See, this is
this is what we're talking about, though. It's
like, yes. Functionally, it's the same thing, but
now it is coded on a platform that's
not gonna go down, and it's Clay's job
to make sure that it's always working. If
you're running it on your GrokBot's computer, if
the computer has to restart and, you know,
you get an update or something and maybe
it wipes the memory of it,
you don't know. You're gonna have to rebuild
it. When it's on clay, it's just always
there and it's gonna persist. And so that's
why we do it on there.
How accurate is Jev with cleaning these lists?
So
I have found it to be incredibly accurate.
What I always do whenever we're we're building
prompts for anything is I have AI write
the prompt for me. Quick tip. You always
want the AI to, self optimize for cached
inputs so you could save and and use
that Google or AskCHP or whatever your model
is to to know what a cached input
is.
And,
I have it create the prompt. I don't
write the prompts anymore. And then I'll just
tell it, alright. Show me the first
50 outputs from this. If we're doing company
ICP classification, I wanna see the first 50
companies. If we're writing messaging with AI, I
wanna see the first 50 messages, whatever it
is. And then I have a skill personally
that made, like, a Tinder style thing that
I'm literally like, this is a good output.
This is a bad output. This is a
good output. This is a bad output. This
is a bad output. This is a good
output. This is a bad output. And I
just turn on whisper flow, and I kinda
just talk through it the entire time. So
I get a transcript of it as well.
And so then if it's a good company,
it knows my skill has taught it to
say, like, okay. This is a good company.
Remember that. And if it's a bad company,
it does the same thing. And then my
whisper flow transcript will, like, add color into
why it's a bad company. And then we
keep going until I'm super happy with that
50 company output. It writes the prompt, and
then I release it into the wild with
Jeff. Maybe the largest ICP classification we've done
so far is on, like, a 100,000 companies.
And everything I manually reviewed I mean, if
we wanna spend the time manually reviewing, if
these are bankruptcy lawyers because remember, that's that's
a tough thing to be able to tell.
Is it is it a law firm, or
is it actually a bankruptcy law firm?
I I I'm very confident that it's they're
all gonna be bankruptcy law firms. It was
it was pretty good.
I take ten milligrams of creatine every day,
but I'm thinking about stopping that because I
feel a difference whatsoever. I just wake up
with this.
What is the best way to teach Grocteville
tables? Just like I said, just have it
review with the ClayCLI
your past
workflows
and how you build them, and then have
it, like, write write rules. And it's like,
oh, based on your Clay
building, these are the the preferences that I've
learned. Are these true? And then you could
just, assign those. I think we're trying to
share something on the screen right now.
Yeah.
No no worries about it. I so we
this was very cool, by the way. So
I would like to do more of these
sessions. I've seen in the chat, there's one
of the polls that if you wanna be
basically part of this, either, like, as an
operator or as an agency and kind of,
like, be featured by us, we would love
to collaborate.
So
we have a pop up on the website.
It's just a short form, like, when you
can pitch us an idea.
Right? And then we don't really care, like,
if you, you know, if you're a massive
agency like Eric or if you're a very
small, like like, new agency or, like, a
small operator in a start up. I don't
really care. I just want the best ideas
to be to be featured that they're using
the clay CLI and and whatever cloud codex
or whatever you use. And so feel free
to apply, and and and would love to
have you on on a future episode of
this thing.
Any other questions we should we should answer?
Somebody was asking about email deliverability real quick.
Every I find I'll deliver it just be
a math equation. How many emails did this
domain send? How many replies overall did this
domain get? Anything that's in the, like, our
bottom 30%,
we're just cutting. Like so it's just, like,
we always keep extra domains for customers. Quick
shout out, hypertide.io
lets you warm domains for free. So, you
know, this is for the people who are,
like, super into this, but, you can warm
the domains on hypertide. We literally if we
have to send a thousand emails per day
per customer, we have enough inboxes to send
a thousand emails. We keep enough inboxes to
send 500 emails always warming. And then because
Hypertide lets us warm up the domains for
free, we'll keep the capacity to send, like,
three times their goal warming for free because
it's so cheap, and then we just rotate
in those domains,
over and over and over again.
There's one question,
Eric, about,
do you still use Clay table, or it's
only the workflows? I can answer on the
Clay side, and then maybe you can say
on, like, on your side.
Workflows are,
I think, better for auditability,
which is very important for us.
And so we've started the process slowly to,
like, convert a lot of our tables to
workflows. It's actually very easy to ask the
CLI to do it. Like, they can not
only read and understand what's in the table,
but they can also help you convert it
into workflows.
We haven't transparently shifted a lot of things,
the entire stack there.
Whatever we build new, it's a no brainer.
We use, like in our case, we use
cursor, actually, and,
and and the Clay CLI, which builds a
workflow.
Yeah. Today, we're building everything into workflows.
I can't really think of a time that
I want a workbook.
So, also, you have to think, like, we're
we're pumping through so much volume at all
times that, like, we go over the 50,000
on everything. So it's like we like, the
only time I can really think that I
would want a workbook
on something is like
and maybe this is some feedback for the
Clay team. You you have rate limits on
webhooks,
and sometimes I wanna send webhooks too fast.
So I'm literally, like, setting up a workbook
that catches
webhooks nested into one, so I'm efficient. And
then I'm splitting it, and then I'm sending
it somewhere, and then it's going to work.
Like, that's the kinda silly stuff I would
say that maybe we still use workbooks for.
But, you know, I kind of I I
suppose I digress on that one. Somebody was
asking about their bounce rate has gone up
ever since they switched to the Clay CLI.
I don't know how that would make a
difference. Just make sure that email verification
is put into your workflow. We have a
rule in the company. Even if a customer
comes to us and they say, I got
this list from somewhere and I validated the
emails. Can you launch this? We do not
trust them ever. It's it's always, like, nope.
You got, like, you gotta revalidate it. No
matter like, even if the provider says it's
double verified all these things, just revalidate it.
We mainly are using LeadMagic for our validation
on that.
Why Grokbot versus Claude?
This is like like I said, I'm an
equal opportunist. I have a Grok build account.
I have a Claude subscription. I have a
Codex subscription. I have a Grokbot. I've got,
I've got everything. I've got Cursor at all.
I like so GrokBot came heavily in handy
yesterday when I was traveling with my 10
old son. All of my computers were closed.
I was on the road. He was screaming,
and I could just use a computer that
was in cloud, and it's all done. And
it has all of my memory context and
all those other things. I think the quad
Opus 5.5 release from yesterday is incredibly exciting,
and I think a lot of people should
be checking it out for things like that.
The main thing to talk about here is
if you're running and gunning and you wanna
set up GTM workflows, the fact that the
computer is always on is really useful, and
it could use the browser, and it could
save things and that kind of stuff. But,
also, if you need to segment that and
supplement it with cloud on the cloud or
or codex on the cloud, there's there's other
things that you could be doing there too.
Amazing.
Anything else? Any other questions? Has this replaced
n eight n? Yeah. I've never I've never
even used n eight n, really.
What about replying to emails? Oh, this is
a great, great use case that we I
didn't even think would come up.
GrotBot is awesome at replying to the emails.
So a couple of things. One, they added
a functionality that can catch webhooks so you
can activate
a bot
when the webhook is caught.
And you could teach it and say, oh,
so so when somebody says this, we say
this. When somebody says this, we say this.
You could even, like,
build out the templates for replying to emails
by just saying, hey. Review all of the
past leads that we've gotten in the conversations
I've manually said to them, and then make,
you know, suggestion templates of what you would
do. Then it does that. And then if
you don't have past positive responses, just say,
come up with
things that people might say and how we
would handle them, then you train that. And
then for a little bit, don't just let
it start replying to people. Just give it
say, like, hey. I wanna pilot this for
three
days. Notify me what you would send, and
then I'll confirm it, and then you could
send it. And then do that for three
days. And then once you're at, like, you
know, 10 out of 10 times, it's asking
you what I should say, then,
just let it rip so you can get
under, like, a five minute speed to lead.
Like, you could like, responding to leads is
a fantastic use case for CrockBot.
So a lot of people said that they
would like to get your skill as a,
like, as a repo to reusable.
The good we have good news and bad
news.
The good news is we are literally building
a clay marketplace
where all these skills
that can be used with any, like,
you know, LLM that you're using,
you can literally take them, and they can
help you build the workflow.
And so
the bad news is it's not we we
haven't shipped it yet. So we're gonna be
sharing as a follow-up to the people that
say yes. We're gonna share the actual, like,
you have, like, repo for Eric.
And then,
in a couple of weeks, we hope to
launch the proper marketplace
where that's gonna be the rip of everything
that we talk about, like, so that you
can actually get started, like, immediately.
I hope I didn't overpromise, Eric. Are you
actually gonna share this?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I've already sent to the
team. They have it. Okay. Amazing.
Awesome. Well, thank you so much everyone for
taking the time today. And, Eric, thank you
so much for, being the
the, you know, the
the first
the first, hopefully, of many, and and it
was amazing to see your work. Yeah. Thanks
so much for having me. And then, Peter,
can we just drop the the codes? I
promise people that SpaceX gave us these codes
for a $200 credit for a Grok line.
Yeah. We dropped it. But today, they were
not they were not they were not. Yeah.
They're they're out, but we dropped it. Already
out? Yep.
I will talk to SpaceX.
You guys are crazy.
Come to the next one. Maybe we'll have
Yeah. Okay.
Still put your email in because I turned
it into a wait list. So still put
your email in, and then I'll talk to
SpaceX to see if we can send, a
code to your email from there.
Amazing.
Thank you, everyone. Have a great day. Thank
you, everyone.
Bye bye.